

# Aida Solat UI/UX Designer & Developer

istanbul, Turkey

I hope you do your best during pandemic covid-19 and be safe and happy!

For more than five years, I've been working in the field of different computer systems, including networks, software, hardware, that can have each one a big cloud that provides information and questions in my brain:)

I remember my first work at the Crown corporation for the IT management building. It was a delightful time for me. I thought it was 2011. It was the first time I assembled Crosswire networking! I can't forget and define my feelings. Thank God I am happy and working on UI/UX Designs and Front End Development around mobile applications and web applications using HTML/CSS/javascript/react and other tools and repositories that you can see in my resume.

And my last note:

No one can be as same as yourself. Be the best one.







in https://aidasolat.com/

### **Work Experience**

November 2019 - May 2021

# Web developer Freelance ConlTser Ltd.

Based in Toronto - Contract project

• Working with one of Ontario's largest fleet management businesses in developing a ground

breaking indoor/outdoor automobile tracking solution in multi-storey surroundings using a

A combination of location services using pass-platform classes, JavaScript frameworks and libraries.

• Planned website development, converting mockups into a usable web presence with HTML,

JavaScript and JSON coding.

• Built and styled new mobile-friendly websites, transitioning legacy presentations to

simultaneous mobile-friendly versions.

- Implemented Google- based SEO and ad campaigns to meet budget specifications.
- Collaborated with the marketing department to determine organizational needs and design pages to meet goals.

• Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.

August 2017 - October 2019

# Software Engineer Radin Co.

One of the sub-companies of Hasin Group holdings, IT solution provider Duties:

· Worked on B2B and B2C platforms with focuses on integrating software solutions into five key

areas including banking and payment systems, information technology security services,

telecommunication operating systems, custom software, cybersecurity and

telecommunications hardware.

- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and
- correcting code.
- Configured, installed and tuned switch-based systems for performance in Oracle databases.
- Wrote scripts for daily maintenance activities, including indexes and table analyses.
- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop

improvement plans.

- Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop
- robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Created procedures for system monitoring, recovery, backup and optimization

August 2016 - July 2017

# Software Engineer IdeaCo

Major provider of integrated and centrally managed training solutions Duties :

• Analysis, design, implementation and development of TMS training management system and

LMS Learning Management System

- Production and implementation of e-learning courses
- Design and execution of electronic exams
- Tested programs and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications.
- Created scripts and processes for data integration and maintenance.
- Configured, installed and handled troubleshooting tasks for a variety of different applications.
- Worked with the software development team on reported errors and bugs on newly released

software and assisted in the deployment of release fixes.

- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees.
- Orchestrated efficient large-scale software deployments, including testing features and correcting code

April 2015 - July 2016

# Database Administrator Software Engineering Group Farapayam

Major software solution provider in the field of finance, accounting and office automation

#### Duties:

- Provided L3 support for all financial and accounting software solutions
- Designed and deployed special-purpose custom reports ordered by various clients
- Administered, supported and monitored databases by proactively resolving database issues and

maintaining servers.

- Wrote and maintained technical and functional specifications to document database intentions and requirements.
- Tested programs and databases to identify issues and make necessary

modifications.

- Coordinated with project management staff on database development timelines and project scope.
- Created scripts and processes for data integration and maintenance.
- Modified existing databases to meet unique needs and goals determined during the initial

evaluation and planning process

June 2014 - March 2015

# Software Implementation Specialist

#### Chargoon

Software solution provider for paperless enterprise communication systems Duties:

- Installed, modified and repaired software and hardware to resolve technical issues.
- Trained and supported end-users with software, hardware and network standards and used processes.
- Performed tests of functionality, security and performance of different workstations and devices.
- Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.
- Identified and solved technical issues using a variety of diagnostic tools and tactics.
- Handled computer system troubleshooting and provided technical support to the entire team for computer operations.
- Developed and maintained strong client relationships to deliver exceptional customer service and problem resolution.
- Improved staff morale and reduced employee turnover by 20%

June 2012 - June 2013

# Help Desk Specialist Cultural and Art Organization

#### Duties:

 Created support documentation that empowered and enabled the user community to extend skills, leverage system features and find resolutions to questions without

intervention from the

support team.

 Installed equipment for data communications networks including cabling, wireless routers and

telephone systems.

• Monitored operational and security procedures for numerous computers in the network, related

systems administration and maintenance protocols.

 Performed system maintenance and upgrades, including patches, service packs, hotfixes and

new security configurations.

- Diagnosed and resolved hardware, software and network problems and replaced defective components.
- Travelled to remote office locations to install nodes and implement client software rollouts.
- Configured and maintained network backup and recovery procedures.
- Supported users both locally and by phone with problem resolution and education.

#### Education



2011 - 2016

Islamic Azad University

Bachelor of Science Information
Technology Engineering

#### **Skills**

## Programming

- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- React.js
- ReactNative
- JQuery
- JSON
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS
- Frameworks
- Git

#### Tools

- Firebase
- Figma
- Adobe XD
- Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- JIRA
- SoapUI
- Postman
- Wireshark

#### Database

- MSSQL Server
- MySQL
- Oracle

#### Languages

- English Professional
- Turkish Professional
- Persian Native or Bilingual